

## Contact();

+52 56 2211 2310

Mexico, CDMX

aaronjt@outlook.com

http://www.linkedin.com/in
/aarón-juárez-aa42361ab

#### Skills();

Front-End: HTML, CSS,
JavaScript, Typescript, React,
Vue.js, Next.js, Angular

Back-End: JavaScript,
Typescript, Python, Node JS,
NestJS, FastAPI

DB: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, TypeORM

Mechatronic: ROS, MATLAB,
SolidWorks, LabView, Python,
C++, C

OS: Linux, Windows

Cloud: Azure, AWS, Google Cloud

Data science (Python): AI (TF),
OpenCV, Pandas, NumPy,
Matplotlib, scikit-learn

IDE: Visual Studio Code, Google
Colab, Jupyter notebook

Git-repo: GitHub, Bitbucket

Workflow: Scrum

# Aarón Juárez

Mechatronic engineer, ROS, computer vision, Al and full stack developer.

## Summary

I am a mechatronics engineer graduated from UPIITA in CDMX, I really like development, music and graphic design.

I worked for a year and a half at Intevolution developing virtual assistants and simple interfaces for the front-end with JavaScript and Azure. I did my social service and final engineering project at CINVESTAV Zacatenco developing with some artificial vision nodes and control with ROS.

I worked two years at a Mexican company called The Rocket Code as a full stack developer.

I'm currently working for Tecnológico de Monterrey as a full stack developer.

I prefer to work remotely (open to other proposals), either full-time or part-time.

Please take a look at my portfolio: <a href="https://my-portfolio-rafalamao.vercel.app/">https://my-portfolio-rafalamao.vercel.app/</a>

# Experience

**Tecnológico de Monterrey -** Full Stack Developer 2024 - 202X (current job)

The Rocket Code - Full Stack Developer 2022 - 2024 (2 yrs 6 mos)

Intevolution - Software Developer 2020 - 2021 (1 year)

# Education

Centro de Investigación y de Estudios Avanzados del IPN

Social Service, ROS, Robotics and Automation Engineering · (February 2020 - May 2022)

Unidad Profesional Interdisciplinaria en Ingeniería y Tecnologías Avanzadas del IPN (UPIITA – IPN)

Bachelor's in engineering, Mechatronics (2016 - 2022)

Centro de Estudios Científicos y Tecnológicos No. 7 "Cuauhtémoc" del IPN

Technical, Electrical Installations and Maintenance (2012 - 2015)

## Contact();

- +52 56 2211 2310
- Mexico, CDMX
- aaronjt@outlook.com
- in http://www.linkedin.com/in
  /aarón-juárez-aa42361ab

## **Projects**

- Simultaneous location and mapping in a mobile robot for the exploration of areas affected by disasters: A website made with React.js that aims to graph a 3D point cloud hosted in a GitHub repository, the point cloud was generated by ORBSLAM2. (UPIITA & CINVESTAV).
- Hector Quadrotor Porting: Because Hector Quadrotor (drone simulator) only works with the ROS Melodic version, I generated a porting for this simulator to work with ROS Noetic. (CINVESTAV).
- Virtual Assistant: A virtual assistant was developed in Intevolution, this assistant helps students and teachers manage various processes, the application was developed with JavaScript and Azure services.

(Intevolution).

• Machine vision project: A machine vision project was developed with Python3 and OpenCV on a Raspberry with RTSP cameras for campus access control.

(Intevolution).

# **Published Articles**

 $\Phi$  3D reconstruction of objects with a monocular camera mounted on a drone.

https://repository.uaeh.edu.mx/revistas/index.php/icbi/article/view/9272

 $\Phi$  Solving tasks with drones (simulation).

https://repository.uaeh.edu.mx/revistas/index.php/icbi/article/view/9273



Page 2 of 2